Guide to the Maritime Association of the Port of New York Records 1863-1989 MS 3093
New-York Historical Society
- General Files I-P, 1945 (Offsite-box 27)
  Piers and Warehouses, North Third Street
  Pilots, Harbor
  Port Director, USN Com. F. G. Reinicke
  Port of Boston
- General Files P-Z, 1945 (Offsite-box 28)
  Port Coordinators' Security Group
  Port of New York Contracting Watching Association
  Port of Portland, Oregon
  Port Protection
  Quarantine Service at Rosebank [Staten Island], N.Y.
  Radio Beacon
  Radios in Life Boats
  Recommendation Letters
  Reinicke, Commodore F. G., U.S.N.
  Rivers, Harbors and Piers Committee
  Ryan, Mr. Joseph P., International Longshoremen's Association
  Seamen's Church Institute
  Seatrain Certificate Suit
  Ship Arrivals at the Port of New York
  Shipping Laws
  Sinclair Refining Co.
  Standing & Trade Committees
  Steamship Agents and Operators
  Supreme Court Decisions Underwriters' Case.
  Tilly, D. L, N.Y. Dock Co.
  Towboat Clearing House
  Transportation Association of America
  Unemployment Tax Credits and Benefits
  United Fruit Co.
  U.S. Coast Guard
  U.S. Coast Guard Regulation on Lyle Gun
  U.S. Coast Guard Specifications for Compasses, Magnetic
  U.S. Coast & Geodetic Survey
  U.S. Customs Service
  U.S. Engineers
  U.S. Lines
  U.S. Maritime Commission
  U.S. Merchant Marine Academy
  U.S. Navy
  U.S. Public Health Service
  Warehouses & Piers, North 3rd Street & Metropolitan Avenue, East River & River Street, Brooklyn
  Western Union Telegraph Co.
- General files A-C, 1946 (Offsite-box 29)
  American Bureau of Shipping
  American Merchant Marine Conference
  American Merchant Marine Library Association
  Anti-Trust
  Appointments, New
  Arrivals, Ship
  Atlantic States Shippers Advisory Board
  Auditing Committee
  Baltimore Association of Commerce
  Baltimore Bulletin
  Edward J. Barber
  Baylis, Comm. John S.
  Geo. W. Betts, Jr.
  Board of Directors
  Board of Engineers for Rivers & Harbors
  Bogardus, John A.
  Boston Maritime Association
  Building File
  C. H. Callaghan (Personal)
  Canals, N.Y. State; Cape Cod Canal
  Cape Henry Weather Bureau
  Captain of the Port Orders; Case Bill (Re: Strikes)
  Chamber of Commerce, N.Y.
  Chamber of Commerce, San Diego
  Chesapeake & Delaware Canal
  Clippings, U.M.A.—U.N.
  Coal Trade Freight Report
  Coastwise Shipping
  Commerce & Industry Association of New York
  Commissioners of Pilots
  Corn Exchange Bank; Corps of Engineers, N.Y. District
  C. C. H. Dispatch Commerce Clearing House, Inc.
- General Files D-L, 1946 (Offsite-box 30)
  Fred B. Dalzell
  Department of Commerce, Washington
  Department of Health, City of New York
  Department of Public Work, N.Y.C.
  Department of State
  Duquesne Warehouse Case
  Empire State Association of Commerce
  Employees
  Employment
  Executive Meeting (February 5, 1946)
  Fair Labor Standards Act
  Federal Traffic Bureau
  Foreign Commerce Club
  Capt. George Fried
  Glatzmayer Memorial
  Herman Goldman
  Greater New York Fund
  Hampton Rods Maritime Association, Inc.
  Basil Harris
  Freeman R. Hathaway
  Health Department, City of New York
  Ice Breakers Meeting
  Indemnity Letters
  Inland Rules of Navigation
  International Labor Convention
  Journal of Commerce Annual Shipping Number
  Letterheads
  Life Saving Benevolent Association
  Lightship (Fire Island)
  Longshoremen's Strike
- General Files M-S, 1946 (Offsite-box 31)
  Mariners Family Asylum Card Party
  Moses, Robert
  National Federation of American Shipping
  National Foreign Trade Week
  National Maritime Day
  National Safety Council, Inc.
  Neale, J. H.
  News Clippings
  Newspaper Items
  New York Board of Trade (Aviation Section)
  N.J. Ship Canal
  N.Y. State Maritime Academy
  N.Y. State Waterways Association
  Oil Polution
  Pier K, Weehawken, N.J.
  Pool, Marine Lighters
  Printer
  Rate Orders, U.S. Maritime Commission
  Rates, Revised
  Red Sea Charters
  Rivers & Harbors Committee River Plate and Brazil Conference
  Hugo E. Rogers
  Schedule of Rates for Port of New York
  Sea-Air Committee (Celler Bill)
  Shipbuilders Council of America
  Ship Operator's Association
  Alfred E. Smith Memorial
  Smoking
  Standard Oil Co. of N.J.
  Strikes
  Supervisor of Harbor
- General Files T-Z, 1946 (Offsite-box 32)
  "T" General
  Teletypewriter Rates
  D. L. Tilly
  President Truman
  Trunk Line Association
  "U" General
  U.S. Department of Commerce
  U.S. Maritime Commission (Correspondence)
  U.S. Maritime Commission (General Orders)
  U.S. Maritime Commission (Releases, etc.)
  U.S. Maritime Commission (Ship Sales)
  U.S. Navy, Port Director, N.Y.
  "V" General
  Vickers, Howard L.
  "W" General
  H. W. Warley
  War Shipping Administration (Correspondence)
  War Shipping Administration (Misc. data, releases, etc.)
  Washington Maritime Service
  Watchmen
  "Y" General
- Files 10-42 to 11-8, 1947-1963 (Offsite-box 33)
  Newark Bay Drawbridge, 10–42
  Railroad Heavy-Lift, 10–50
  Tin Plate Rates, 10–51
  Stevedoring Committee Administrative, 11–3
  Stevedoring (Exhibit File), 11–3
  Stevedoring Committee Section A, 11–3
  Coordinating Committee for the Promotion of the Port of New York, 11–4
  Standing & Trade Committee, Section III, 11–5
  Standing & Trade Committees, 11–5
  Steamship Operating Committee (Meetings with Trucking Interests), 11–7
  Steamship Operating Committee (Administrative), 11–7
  Steamship Operating Committee, "Extra Copies," 11–7
  Committee on Admissions (Administrative), 11–8
- Files 11-19 to 11-30, 1951-1965 (Offsite-box 34)
  Complaint Committee, 11–9
  Auditing (Administrative), 11–10
  Finance Committee (Administrative), 11–11
  Foreign Freight Forwarders Committee (Administrative), 11–12
  Floor Committee (Administrative), 11–13
  Law Committee (Administrative), 11–14
  Joint Steamship & Railroad Committee, Section II, 11–15
  Marine Fittings & Dunnage Committee (Administrative), 11–17
  Marine Insurance Committee (Administrative), 11–18
  Purchasing Agents' Committee (Administrative), 11–19
  Ship Brokers' Committee (Administrative), 11–20; Shipbuilding, Engineering, Construction and Repair Committee (Administrative), 11–21
  Steamship Affairs (American) Committee (Administrative), 11–22
  Steamship Affairs (Foreign) Committee (Administrative), 11–23
  Steamship Affairs (Foreign) Committee (Administrative), 11–24
  Tanker Committee (Administrative), 11–25
  Terminal & Warehouse Committee (Administrative), 11–26
  Towboat Committee (Administrative), 11–27
  Traffic Advisory Committee (Administrative), 11–28
  Executive Committee, 11–29
  Purchasing Agent Committee, 11–30.
- Files 11-31 to 12-2, 15-2, Resignations, 1948-1967 (Offsite-box 35)
  Commission on Foreign Economic Policy-Committee, 11–31
  Banking Committee, 11–32
  Admission Committee, 11–33
  Packaging Committee (Exhibit File), 11–34–A
  Packaging Committee, 11–34
  International Study Committee, 11–35
  Bridge-to-Bridge Radiotelephone Communication, 11–36
  Safety Program, 12–0
  Safety Exhibit, 12–0–A
  National Safety Council, 12–1
  National Safety Council (Exhibits), 12–1–A
  Heroism Awards Committee, 12–2
  Resignations (1962–1963).
- Membership files, 15-0-981 to 15-0-1875, 1953-1961 (Offsite-box 36)
  Membership 15–0–444 through 601, Section 3
  Membership 15–0–602 through 770, Section 4
  Membership 15–0–771 through 980, Section 5
  Membership 15–0–981 through 1656, Section 6
  Membership 15–0–1567 through 1874, Section 7
  Membership 15–0–1875 through 2065, Section 8
- Files 15-2 to 16-0, Resignations, 1947-1972 (Offsite-box 37)
  Resignations (1957–1972)
  Membership Resignations, 15–2
  Obituary, Section A, 16–0
  Obituary, Section II, 16–0
  Obituary, Section III, 16–0
- Membership files, 15-0-2066 to 15-1, 1950-1964 (Offsite-box 38)
  Membership 15–0–2066 through 2191, Section 9
  Membership 15–0–2192, Section 10
  Membership (New Members) 15–1 (1 to 396), Section 1
  Membership (New Members) 15–1 (397 through 521), Section 2
- Expenses, golf files, circa 1970-1979 (Offsite-box 39)
- Correspondence, newspaper clippings, paid accounts, ship reporting fees, 1920-1975 (Offsite-box 40)
- Arrivals to New York, 1947-1950 (Offsite-box 41)
- Arrivals to New York, 1951, 1956-1957 (Offsite-box 42)
- Arrivals to New York, 1952-1955 (Offsite-box 43)
- Arrivals to New York, Casualties, 1958-1959, 1948-1964 (Offsite-box 44)
- Arrivals to New York, 1960-1962 (Offsite-box 45)
- Arrivals to New York, 1963-1965 (Offsite-box 46)
- Arrivals to New York, 1966-1968 (Offsite-box 47)
- Arrivals to New York, Berthings, 1968-1970 (Offsite-box 48)
- Arrivals to New York, 1970-1971, 1973 (Offsite-box 49)
- Arrivals to New York, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 50)
- Arrivals to New York, 1973-1975 (Offsite-box 51)
- Arrivals to New York, 1980-1983 (Offsite-box 52)
- Arrivals and Departures, 1987-1989 (Offsite-box 53)
- Departures from New York, 1947-1950 (Offsite-box 54)
- Departures from New York, 1951-1954 (Offsite-box 55)
- Departures from New York, 1955-1957 (Offsite-box 56)
- Departures from New York, 1958-1960 (Offsite-box 57)
- Departures from New York, 1961-1963 (Offsite-box 58)
- Departures from New York, 1964-1966 (Offsite-box 59)
- Departures from New York, 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 60)
- Departures from New York, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 61)
- Departures from New York, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 62)
- Departures from New York, 1973-1975 (Offsite-box 63)
- Departures from New York, 1980-1983 (Offsite-box 64)
- Departures from New York, Transportings, Arrivals, 1984-1986 (Offsite-box 65)
- Berthings, weekly reports, 1966-1970 (Offsite-box 66)
- Berthings, 1971-1973 (Offsite-box 67)
- Berthings, 1980-1982 (Offsite-box 68)
- Berthings, 1983-1984, 1986 (Offsite-box 69)
- Berthings, transportings, casualties, 1987-1989 (Offsite-box 70)
- Casualties, 1968-1970 (Offsite-box 71)
- Casualties, 1971-1973 (Offsite-box 72)
- Casualties, 1982-1984 (Offsite-box 73)
- Breakdowns February-April, 1948 (Offsite-box 74)
- Breakdowns May-July, 1948 (Offsite-box 75)
- Breakdowns July-October, 1948 (Offsite-box 76)
- Files on Lloyd's Shipping Index, war built vessels, 1940-1967 (Box 77)
- Files on Lloyd's Shipping Index, 1968-1971 (Box 78)
- Lloyd's casualties, 1972-1974 (Box 79)
- Lloyd's casualties, 1974-1975 (Box 80)
- Lloyd's casualties, 1976-1979 (Box 81)
- Lloyd's casualties, 1977-1978 (Box 82)
- Lloyd's casualties, 1979-1980 (Box 83)
- Lloyd's casualties, 1980-1981 (Box 84)
- Lloyd's casualties, 1981, 1986 (Box 85)
- American Bureau of Shipping record books (Offsite-box 86)
- American Bureau of Shipping supplements, 1976 (Offsite-box 87)
- Lloyd's Shipping Index, circa 1960-1980 (Box 88)
- Lloyd's Shipping Index, 1985-1987 (Box 89)
- American Bureau of Shipping supplements, 1969-1970, 1972, 1974, 1976 (Offsite-box 90)
- Lloyd's Shipping Index, circa 1980-1989 (Box 91)
- American Bureau of Shipping record books, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 92)
- Board of Directors minutes, 1928-1933 (Offsite-box 93)
- Board of Directors minutes, 1937 (Offsite-box 94)
- Lloyd's Shipping Index (Box 95)
- Board of Directors minutes, 1920-1928 (Offsite-box 96)
- Lloyd's Shipping Index, circa 1980-1989 (Box 97)
- Arrivals and Departures, 1981-1984 (Offsite-box 98)
- Long Island Sound arrivals, ship data sheets, 1985-1989 (Offsite-box 99)
- Germanischer Lloyd (Box 100)
- Maritime Exchange Bulletin (Offsite-box 101)
- Maritime Exchange Bulletin (Offsite-box 102)
- Maritime Exchange Bulletin (Offsite-box 103)
- Annual meeting books (Offsite-box 104)
- Books (Offsite-box 105)
- Books (Offsite-box 106)
- Books (Offsite-box 107)
- Books (Offsite-box 108)
- Books (Offsite-box 109)
- Germanischer Lloyd (Box 110)
- Journals and other publications (Offsite-box 111)
- Port of New York publications, reports (Offsite-box 112)
- Lloyd's Confidential Index (Box 113)
- Books, guides, registers (Offsite-box 114)
- Lloyd's Register (yachts), calendar (Box 115)
- Registers, Shipowners Association minutes (Offsite-box 116)
- Reports, journals (Offsite-box 117)
- Registers, directories (Offsite-box 118)
- Naval Institute proceedings, journals, reports (Offsite-box 119)
- Receipts, law reports (Offsite-box 120)
- Campaign to Improve Methods of Export pamphlets (Offsite-box 121)
- Campaign to Improve Methods of Export pamphlets (Offsite-box 122)